<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
    <description>Filtered feed containing only Breakfast Wrap episodes from Radio National Breakfast</description>
    <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 02:17:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/breakfast-wrap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <atom:link href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" rel="hub"/>
    <podcast:guid>f95d7b89-e1ee-554c-be7f-f126f0b92dae</podcast:guid>
    <image>
      <url>https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg</url>
      <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg"/>
    <itunes:author>ABC Radio National</itunes:author>
    <itunes:category text="News"/>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>ABC Radio National</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>podcasts@abc.net.au</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The battle for Hollywood</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The battle for the future of Hollywood is heating up this morning after Paramount mounted a hostile bid worth US$108 billion for Warner Bros Discovery, just days after Netflix agreed to buy out the media giant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paramount says it's taking its bid straight to Warner Bros shareholders, asking them to reject the Netflix deal valued at more than US$70 billion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce has formally joined One Nation, after leaving the Nationals last month.The Member for New England intends to run on One Nation's Senate ticket for New South Wales at the next federal election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026538</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026538</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fp/Z/09.mp3" length="33661103" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:22</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The emerging scale of Indonesia's cyclone devastation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The death toll continues to rise on the Indonesian island of Sumatra after the region was devastated by Cyclone Senyar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 900 people have been killed in floods and landslides, with more than a million people displaced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll head to Indonesia to hear what is planned for the country's cyclone recovery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, federal cabinet is expected to consider proposals for an east coast gas reserve today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plus, we'll find out how to support your child through the social media ban.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And 24-year-old Victorian Oscar Piastri has finished second in the season-ending Abu Dhabi Grand Prix, leaving him third overall in Formula One the championship. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026544</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026544</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fn/Z/rd.mp3" length="35334959" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:32</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia receives AUKUS review from US</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agenda-setting news coverage, breaking news and stories impacting the lives of all Australians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026726</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026726</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fl/Z/b3.mp3" length="56087040" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:12</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia's fresh commitment to Ukraine</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coverage and analysis of national and international events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026682</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026682</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fk/Z/20.mp3" length="56855040" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:30</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Teens flock to Lemon8 and Yope platforms</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The list of social media platforms banned for kids under 16 years old could grow ahead of next week's lockout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The eSafety Commissioner has written to two platforms — Lemon8 and Yope — recommending they self-assess to determine if they fall under new laws that begin on December 10. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, more than 1300 people have been killed and hundreds of thousands displaced by devastating flooding and landslides across four countries in Asia in recent days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And with the government's national road map for AI now public, how is the industry preparing to make the most of the windfall, specifically in regards to data centres. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026530</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026530</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fi/Z/s7.mp3" length="35139119" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:24</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: AI plan unveiled</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government has released its National AI Plan, describing it &quot;comprehensive road-map&quot; to unlock the full potential of the technology for all Australians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, according to the Australian Medical Association (AMA), misinformation, anti-science sentiments and vaccine fatigue have eroded the public's trust in vaccines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it's been described as one of the biggest reforms to defence in five decades, but why is not everyone sold on the government's latest change to defence procurement. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And why have farmers been pushing for 'right to repair' protections?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026548</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106026548</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fh/Z/if.mp3" length="35443247" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:36</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Will the government order an independent childcare review</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year the ABC's Four Corners program exposed cases of child abuse and alleged child abuse, neglect, and injury within the childcare sector, highlighting critical gaps in safety and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Productivity Commission recommended an independent review of national childcare standards, but the federal government is yet to commit to such a review.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the federal opposition is gearing up for a new political fight on immigration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then overseas, Venezuela has condemned US President Donald Trump's latest warning about its airspace, after Mr Trump posted online that the skies around the country should be treated as closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll also find out about tension between Japan and China. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106023702</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106023702</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fg/Z/d7.mp3" length="35728367" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:48</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: How the government secured its environmental deal</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A long-awaited overhaul of federal environment laws passed the Senate yesterday, after the government struck a deal with the Greens. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll hear from the man who wrote the blueprint for the revamp of the Environmental Protection and Biodiversity Conservation Act. We'll also hear from the Environment Minister Murray Watt and the Greens environment spokesperson Sarah Hanson-Young. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, The Lebanese prime minister has criticised Hezbollah overnight for failing to disarm, saying that its refusal to do so is hurting his country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes as Israel carried out more strikes in Lebanon this week, killing civilians; the United Naitons has now confirmed at least 127 deaths since last year's ceasefire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And for the third consecutive season, North Melbourne and Brisbane will face off in the AFLW grand final - the Lions' seventh decider in the league's first 10 seasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106014514</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106014514</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fd/Z/t9.mp3" length="35363183" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:33</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Labor strikes environmental laws deal</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says Labor has struck a deal to overhaul the nation's outdated environmental protection laws.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Albanese says the laws will pass the Senate today, more than five years after Graeme Samuel handed down a review into the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, a massive high-rise apartment fire in Hong Kong's Tai Po district has killed at least 44 people and left hundreds more missing, with firefighters continuing to battle the blaze, which has spread across multiple buildings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, Optus crews spent hours repairing a mobile phone outage for more than 14,000 services yesterday. We hear from the former boss of the consumer watchdog. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Tasmania's fiscal future is back in the spotlight, after the state's credit rating dropped to the lowest in the country, alongside the Northern Territory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106013014</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106013014</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fc/Z/kn.mp3" length="35341295" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:32</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: US will monitor immigrant crime in Australia</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data on crimes committed by migrants in Australia will be tracked by the United States, following a directive from the Trump Administration. The ABC has confirmed the US Embassy in Canberra has been given the directive along with embassies in several other western nations, including New Zealand and Canada. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The CEO of the Association of Mining and Exploration Companies, Warren Pearce, has called on the parliament to pass the government's long-awaited environmental reforms. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Pearce says there is a sense of urgency for a deal to be made this week on the final sitting week of 2025. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Nigeria's president says all 24 schoolgirls who were abducted by armed assailants from a government boarding school last week in Kebbi, in the country's north-west, have been rescued.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And, the University of Canberra has announced it will develop a large-scale aged care community next to the University of Canberra Hospital, as part of a 100-year agreement to bring residents closer to where healthcare staff are trained.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106008296</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106008296</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fb/Z/e1.mp3" length="34195055" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:44</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Why the BOM website cost $96 million</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Meteorology is weathering a storm of its own over its controversial website redesign. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has revealed the cost is $96.5 million, after initially saying the redesign cost $4 million.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Melissa Clarke wraps the reaction to One Nation leader Pauline Hanson wearing a burqa in the Senate, her latest parliamentary stunt. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we hear from Oscar-winning actor Russel Crowe about his latest film.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106003478</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106003478</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/fa/Z/97.mp3" length="35328047" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:31</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Darwin weathers its strongest cyclone in decades</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clean-up efforts have begun in the Top End after Tropical Cyclone Fina swept through the Northern Territory at category three strength.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fina was the NT's strongest cyclone to pass Darwin since the devastating Cyclone Tracy in 1974.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, if you were to use just one word, how would you describe the last federal election? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to veteran journalist, Niki Savva, it was an earthquake which shook the nation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In her fifth book, the award-winning author reflects on the 2025 election, and the subsequent aftershocks that continue to be felt in the nation's capital and beyond. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a panel of fertility experts has developed the first Australian evidence-based guidelines on male fertility to assist specialists in finding the root causes of infertility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105998840</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105998840</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f9/Z/1t.mp3" length="23681664" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Another state Liberal leader gets the boot</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First-term MP Kellie Sloane has become the new leader of the New South Wales Liberals, following former leader Mark Speakman's decision to step down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It follows Jess Wilson taking over for Brad Battin as the Victorian Liberal leader. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll hear from the Sydney Morning Herald's state political editor, and a senior federal Liberal, as the outgoing premier partially blames the federal wing for his demise. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the federal government has given up a multi-year campaign to host next year's COP31 climate summit, ceding hosting rights to Türkiye.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the details of a deal with Türkiye are still being finalised, Minister for Climate Change and Energy Chris Bowen says he will still lead negotiations at the summit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Greens argue that the government's heart was never really in it, and the City of Adelaide shares why they're disappointed to lose out to Istanbul. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990676</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990676</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f6/Z/id.mp3" length="35237046" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:28</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Why Turkiye wants to host COP31</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The COP31 climate summit will not be held in Australia, but in a deal struck with Turkiye, Climate Change Minister Chris Bowen will be appointed President of next year's meeting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap will find out why Turkiye wants to host the summit and put itself at the center of global climate action negotiations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990680</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990680</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f5/Z/dt.mp3" length="34844207" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:11</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Sussan Ley denies Libs taking cues from One Nation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Opposition leader Sussan Ley denies the party is taking its lead from Pauline Hanson's One Nation party, as it seeks to cover lost ground on net-zero and now immigration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liberal leader also faces questions about her security in the top job, as a key ally quits the party in protest over undermining of the leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear our extened interview with Sussan Ley. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we'll also speak to the CEO of the CSIRO as it plans to shed hundreds of staff and scale back research programs in a significant restructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll find out what the UN Security Council's endorsement of the US proposal for Gaza means for people on the ground. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990682</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990682</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f3/Z/ur.mp3" length="34527407" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:58</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Pauline Hanson says Coalition following One Nation's lead</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New polling published in the Australian Financial Review shows One Nation is more trusted than Labor or the Coalition to deal with the influx of migrants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response, Pauline Hanson says her party has been &quot;setting the agenda for many years now&quot; from migration, to climate change and the Voice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Everything that we've set in place, the Coalition have followed our lead … this is just another one.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes as the Coalition mulls its own immigration policy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll hear about the polling from Redbridge's Tony Barry, and get analysis from Melissa Clarke. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990234</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105990234</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f2/Z/rv.mp3" length="34585583" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:01</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Coalition reopens climate wars</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Liberal and National parties have announced their new joint climate and energy policy, dumping a commitment to net zero emissions by 2050. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, the policy promises to reduce emissions &quot;year on year,&quot; considering the &quot;real performance&quot; of other developed countries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opposition leader Sussan Ley has also said affordability would be at the heart of the Coalition's plan, though she did not outline when or by how much power bills should be reduced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, a Monash University study has found lifesaving programs are either inaccessible or not inclusive to tourists and migrants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And US President Donald Trump has withdrawn his support for Marjorie Taylor Greene, blasting the Georgia congresswoman as a &quot;traitor&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105988724</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105988724</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/f1/Z/mo.mp3" length="35256623" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:28</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: BBC apology and Libs ditch net-zero</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BBC has rejected demands for financial compensation by US President Donald Trump after broadcasting a program last year that contained a misleading edit of his speech on the day of the Capitol riots. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll hear from a former BBC Newsnight editor and co-host of the News Agents podcast Lewis Goodall. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, as the Liberals formally ditch net-zero by 2050, we'll speak with the minister in charge of the Coalition's energy and emissions policy, who's been wrangling Liberal negotiations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll also find out the state of play in Tasmania, as disussions around the state's proposed stadium reach parliament. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105974866</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105974866</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/ev/Z/j2.mp3" length="35055023" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:20</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Victoria's 'adult time for violent crime' laws under scrutiny</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&quot;Adult Crime, Adult Time&quot; was a policy that the Queensland LNP took to last year's state election and won.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, ahead of Victoria's state election next year, Premier Jacinta Allan has announced a similar policy to help tackle rising youth crime in the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll explore than, and the Liberals ministerial meeting on net-zero by 2050. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes after Liberal MPs and senators met for almost five hours at Parliament House yesterday, with the majority of attendees calling for the target to be abandoned. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, two years ago the Matildas were the most-watched sporting team in the country as they battled to the semi-finals of the World Cup in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a new report into the domestic football league warns the sport may have squandered that attention, with crowds in decline and players among the lowest-earning female athletes in the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Australia has struck a bilateral security deal with Indonesia, the second major treaty Australia has negotiated in as many months.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister Anthony Albanese announced the deal alongside Indonesia's President Prabowo Subianto in Sydney.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105972360</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105972360</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/eu/Z/cg.mp3" length="35701295" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:47</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Liberals converge on Canberra for net-zero talks</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liberal party members are gathering today in Canberra to discuss their energy and climate policies, in the first of a series of meetings this week aiming to settle the Coalition's energy position.It is uncertain whether the Liberals will follow the Nationals and dump their commitment to net zero emissions by 2050.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liberal Senator for South Australia, Leah Blythe, says she supports Sussan Ley and has &quot;full confidence&quot; in the Opposition Leader, regardless of the outcome of the policy debate. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke has confirmed he met with Nauru's President David Adeang in Canberra, after the Pacific Island nation's leader made an unannounced visit to Parliament House yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The visit comes after reporting by Nine newspapers that criminal bikie gangs were awarded a lucrative contract to provide security for former immigration detainees transferred to Nauru.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plus we'll cross the Tasman to hear about a decision to expel two of New Zealand's Te Pāti Maori MPs that has left the party in disarray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Ahmed Al-Sharaa has become the first Syrian leader ever welcomed to the White House, where he's held landmark talks with US President Donald Trump on rebuilding ties with the US, and cooperating in the fight against the Islamic State group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105968218</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105968218</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/et/Z/8v.mp3" length="35111471" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:22</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The dismissal of Gough Whitlam, 50 years on</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coverage and analysis of national and international events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105963544</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105963544</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/es/Z/83.mp3" length="58834560" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
