<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
    <description>Filtered feed containing only Breakfast Wrap episodes from Radio National Breakfast</description>
    <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 02:51:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/breakfast-wrap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <atom:link href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" rel="hub"/>
    <podcast:guid>f95d7b89-e1ee-554c-be7f-f126f0b92dae</podcast:guid>
    <image>
      <url>https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg</url>
      <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/</link>
    </image>
    <itunes:image href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg"/>
    <itunes:author>ABC Radio National</itunes:author>
    <itunes:category text="News"/>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>ABC Radio National</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>podcasts@abc.net.au</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Why is inflation so hot?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Slightly higher than expected inflation in January has kept pressure on the Reserve Bank to inflict another interest rate hike and increased scrutiny of the federal government's economic management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll unpack the latest figures and hear from the Treasurer and Shadow Treasurer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the Prime Minister is in hot water over comments he's made about a former Australian of the Year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And debate is intensifying in Tasmania over the use of antibiotics in the salmon industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106330420</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106330420</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/i2/Z/hk.mp3" length="35282549" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:30</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Why there's more UK Epstein fallout than in the US</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why has the Epstein files lead to a more significant fallout in the UK, but not in the US?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK, a former prince and a former ambassador face criminal investigations over their links to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, while a number of government officials have lost their jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But in the US, prominent figures whose names come up thousands of times in the latest tranche of files - released by the US Department of Justice - remain unscathed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear from the former White House ethics lawyer Richard Painter. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we turn to the trial of Rodrigo Duterte at the International Criminal Court. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We cover the start of the Royal Commission into Antisemitism and Social Cohesion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And ask why AI development is still outpacing regulation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106329236</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106329236</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/i1/Z/be.mp3" length="35357429" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:33</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia's role in removing Andrew from succession</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What role could Australia play in removing former prince Andrew from the &quot;royal batting lineup&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We get analysis from Tom Crowley and Anne Twomey following news that Prime Minister Anthony Albanese sent his British counterpart a letter confirming Australia would support the removal of Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line of succession to the British throne.Mr Albanese has told the ABC he wants Australia to be the first to country to offer its support to the move. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the federal government is under pressure from the opposition to do more to block the return of 34 Australians in Syria with links to the Islamic State terrorist group. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And there's a new wave of violence across Mexico today, after one of the world's most-wanted drug traffickers - the cartel boss known as El Mencho - was killed by security forces on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106323172</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106323172</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/i0/Z/3i.mp3" length="34257263" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:47</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Four years of the war in Ukraine</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the 24th of February 2022, after months of mounting tensions, Russian President Vladimir Putin launched an invasion of Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four years on and the invasion has become a war of attrition; as Ukraine fights to reclaim its territory from Russia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear from the Ukrainian and European Ambassadors to Australia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we turn to federal politics with National Party Leader David Littleproud. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also return to two big international stories from last week, Sudan and the arrest of Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106320120</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106320120</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hu/Z/t3.mp3" length="35525621" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:40</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Emily Maitlis on Andrew's arrest</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We cover the extraordinary news of the arrest of Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor with the journalist who once interviewed him. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2019 BBC Newsnight interview with the then Prince, was widely regarded as a car crash that would lead to Andrew's demise. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emily Maitlis shares her shock at his arrest. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we turn to Sudan as a UN probe finds atrocities committed bear the hallmarks of genocide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106310922</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106310922</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hr/Z/5r.mp3" length="35082677" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:21</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Pauline Hanson's Muslim comments condemned</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One Nation leader Pauline Hanson is facing widespread criticism this week for suggesting there were no good Muslims in Australia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She has since issued a partial apology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Breakfast Wrap we hear from the Muslim community in Western Sydney, and capture the political condemnation across the aisle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Australia's low debt status is being threatened; with the combination of federal and state debt heading towards levels not seen since World War Two. We'll get the latest analysis. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the federal government has temporarily banned an Australian citizen with links to the Islamic State group from returning home from Syria. So for those who do return, what security measures are in place? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106306986</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106306986</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hp/Z/o8.mp3" length="35424245" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:35</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Government under pressure over return of IS-linked families</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An independent UN Commissioner has responded to PM Anthony Albanese's insistence that the Australian government will not help the families with links to Islamic State trying to return home from Syria. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Albanese told the ABC this week that &quot;if you make your bed, you lie in it&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Independent UN Commissioner Fionnuala Ní Aoláin told Radio National Breakfast, &quot;&quot;these women are victims too, and their children are absolutely victims.&quot; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;They didn't choose their beds, their beds were made for them.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hear the extended interview in the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we rememberr the life and legacy of the late Reverend Jesse Jackson, who's died at the age of 84. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106302360</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106302360</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/ho/Z/ik.mp3" length="35446127" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:36</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The search for Nancy Guthrie</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More than a fortnight after the kidnapping of an American TV personality's mother, we hear from a former FBI special agent about why this is such an unusual case. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we head to Syria, for the latest on the IS-linked families trying to return to Australia. A journalist speaking to the families shares her insights. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we question a Liberal politician over an alleged draft proposal to restrict migration from certain regions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106294750</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106294750</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hn/Z/b9.mp3" length="33940470" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:34</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Why a US climate reversal 'is a very big deal'</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We hear from the former boss of the US EPA following the Trump administration removing a cornerstone of climate regulation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, to federal politics. The Treasurer Jim Chalmers discusses some fo the early policy positions put foward by the new leadership of the Liberal Party. We also speak with the Vice President of the Liberal Party and the independent hoping to win Sussan's Ley's seat of Farrer. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106293802</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106293802</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hm/Z/3h.mp3" length="35114351" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:23</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Angus Taylor wins Liberal leadership</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap shares fresh analysis following Angus Taylor winning the Liberal leadership  34 votes to 17, with Jane Hume elected deputy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Featuring commentary from Niki Savva and two Liberal politicians speaking before the vote, we try to understand the position the Liberal party is in and where they need to go now. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, its a big morning in parliament for other reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is18 years since the government's apology to the Stolen Generations. We feature an interview with the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Social Justice Commissioner. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106284562</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106284562</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hj/Z/p4.mp3" length="11312832" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Liberal leadership challenge is on</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Start each day with comprehensive coverage and analysis of natHear fresh political analysis from Mel Clarke as Angus Taylor confirms  that he will challenge Sussan Ley for the Liberal leadership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several Liberal frontbenchers have resigned from their roles and a leadership vote could be held as soon as today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Muslim community leaders are calling for an apology over the actions of some police officers at Monday night's protests during the Israeli president's visit to Sydney.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And more than 127 million people in Bangladesh are expected to vote today to pick the country's next leader and government, in what has been described as the first proper poll since 2008.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.ional and international events, and hear interviews with the people who matter today&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/liberal-leadership-challenge-is-on/106278072</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/liberal-leadership-challenge-is-on/106278072</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hi/Z/h4.mp3" length="35393135" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:34</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Turnbull on social cohesion and Liberal leadership</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the Breakfast Wrap features an interview with former Australian Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, exploring two major stories. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear his response to protests in Sydney against the Israeli President's visit to Australia, and speculation of a leadership challenge in the Liberal Party. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we follow his comments, hearing from the NSW government and the Deputy Foreign Minister to Israel Sharren Haskel. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/breakfast-wrap/106330470</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/breakfast-wrap/106330470</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hh/Z/5s.mp3" length="11326080" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Scrutiny over NSW police protest response</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A NSW state politician claims she was &quot;beaten&quot; by police at a protest on Monday night demonstrating the Israeli president's visit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear from Greens MP Abigail Boyd, and others in the crowd, as the Premier Chris Minns defends the response by NSW police. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the son of jailed Hong Kong democracy activist Jimmy Lai speaks to Radio National Breakfast following the sentencing of his father to 20 years in jail. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we break down the latest on the Epstein saga out of the UK, as King Charles wades in and PM Keir Starmer fends off political attacks. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106272136</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106272136</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hf/Z/ta.mp3" length="35436341" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:36</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Coalition back together, again.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Coalition comes back together after a 17 day split, but a new Newspoll shows its primary vote at historic lows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear from Liberal Shadow Minister James McGrath and Deputy Nationals Leader Kevin Hogan. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll finish up with the story of Farm Angels, a part of the Changing Australia series. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast-wrap-coalition-back-together-again/106268524</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast-wrap-coalition-back-together-again/106268524</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/he/Z/pk.mp3" length="11531904" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:01</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: 'Terror act', the attempted bombing of a protest</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally in Perth last week has been declared a terrorist act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The West Australian Premier Roger Cook says a 31-year-old man accused of throwing the homemade bomb has now been charged with 'engaging in a terrorist act'. We'll hear from Malarndirri McCarthy, the  Minister for Indigenous Australians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, an interview with the US judge who ordered the release of a five year old boy and his father from immigration detention after they were detained by ICE. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll finish up talking cryptocurrency as one of the largest platforms accusing Australian banks of stifling competition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106256526</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106256526</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hc/Z/fh.mp3" length="35203061" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:26</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Should Australia arrest the Israeli president?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;UN Commissioner Chris Sidoti is leading calls for Australia to arrest the President of Israel Isaac Herzog when he lands in the country this weekend. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the visit, Mr Sidoti shares why he thinks Australia is obliged to act on the head of state's comments about Gaza. We'll get a response from the Foreign Minister Penny Wong and a senior Liberal shadow minister. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the list of the world's rich and powerful who had alleged links to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein is growing as journalists continue to sift through millions of unclassified documents released by the U-S government last week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And what do you know about Claude AI? We'll find out why its rattled investors around the world. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106252454</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106252454</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/hb/Z/8u.mp3" length="34545845" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:59</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The rate rise blame game</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With interest rates up once again, there are calls from the opposition and business for the government to lower spending, while experts say that's not the true culprit for rising inflation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today the Breakfast Wrap hears from a former policy advisor to the Prime Minister's office, as well as both sides of the political fence. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has extended controversial restrictions on public assembly for another fortnight quoting &quot;significant risk to community safety&quot;. That period takes in a four-day visit from Israeli President Isaac Herzog who arrives on Sunday. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NSW Opposition shares its perspective. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106248040</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106248040</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/ha/Z/59.mp3" length="11419584" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: What's the right response to an alleged attempted bombing?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Independent Senator Lidia Thorpe has slammed the federal government's initial response to an alleged attempted bombing in Perth as &quot;very poor&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She will today pursue a motion in the Senate to condemn the alleged attack that is now being investigated as a potential terrorist attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Liberal leader Sussan Ley and Nationals leader David Littleproud met last night to try and hash out the possibility of the Coalition reforming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And as the reconciliation process continues, some polling shows One Nation's primary vote is outperforming the former Coalition parties. We'll hear from both parties, and ABC election analyst emeritus Antony Green. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106246230</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106246230</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h8/Z/uq.mp3" length="34270518" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:47</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Epstein survivors 'devastated' by leaked names</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hear from the lawyer for some of the victims of convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gloria Allred says some her clients are devastated after their names were leaked in the latest batch of files released by the US Department of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Nationals leader David Littleproud is widely expected to survive a leadership challenge brought by Queensland MP Colin Boyce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Opposition Leader Sussan Ley has appointed a temporary shadow ministry to fill roles vacated by the Nationals warning that she will permanently fill the positions if the coalition doesn't reunite within a week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106243204</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106243204</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h7/Z/m5.mp3" length="34964021" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:00</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Facing your would be-assassin</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We hear from Iranian-American dissident and journalist Masih Alinejad after the sentencing of her would-be assassin in an American court. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we turn to the situation in Iran and the threats coming out of Washington. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back home the Liberal and National parties woes continue. We hear from a Liberal standing by leader Sussan Ley. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106232528</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106232528</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h5/Z/f4.mp3" length="35367798" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:33</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The MP challenging the Nationals Leadership</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coverage and analysis of national and international events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start each day with comprehensive coverage and analysis of national and international events, and hear interviews with the people who matter today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationals backbencher Colin Boyce said he will move a spill motion to challenge David Littleproud for the leadership of the party next week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Littleproud says he's &quot;always respected&quot; the party room's &quot;decisions and direction&quot;, including &quot;the right to voice different opinions&quot; - and he stands by his record as Nationals leader. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, pressure on Opposition Leader Sussan Ley has intensified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two most likely leadership contenders - Andrew Hastie and Angus Taylor - aren't ruling out a tilt ahead of parliament resuming next week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turning to WA where authorities have confirmed they're investigating the alleged throwing of a bomb into a crowd at an Invasion Day rally in Perth as a &quot;potential terrorist act&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 31-year old man has been charged with endangering lives or safety, and he's also been charged with making or possessing explosives under suspicious circumstances in connection with the Australia Day incident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overseas US President Donald Trump has signalled he wants to ease tensions in Minneapolis following the fatal shooting of American citizen Alex Pretti.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The killing of Mr Pretti has reignited local protests in Minneapolis and across the country, and comes just weeks after Renee Good was killed by an Immigration and Customs Enforcement official in the same city.Meanwhile a former senior lawyer says the latest investigation into the Minnesota governor and Minneapolis mayor is about shifting the focus of the events. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106228462</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106228462</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h4/Z/do.mp3" length="34905846" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:14</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Former ICE director questions agency's response</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;US President Donald Trump says he wants an &quot;honourable and honest&quot; investigation into the killing of protester Alex Pretti by federal agents in Minneapolis. Mr Trump's so-called &quot;border tsar&quot; Tom Homan has arrived in Minneapolis to lead the immigration crackdown, replacing Border Patrol commander Gregory Bovino. The Breakfast Wrap speaks to a former director of ICE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, former Prime Minister Scott Morrison has urged Muslim leaders to accredit preachers, to translate religious teachings into English and to clamp down on links to foreign Islamist groups. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the program opposition front bencher Andrew Bragg supports the notion, saying that &quot;the Australian Muslim community has to take some responsibility for the behaviours we've seen exhibited over the last couple of decades&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And overseas, the political fallout continues in the UK, after former British home secretary Suella Braverman became the latest MP to defect from the Conservatives to join Nigel Farage's Reform UK party this week.Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106225670</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106225670</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h3/Z/9s.mp3" length="33401327" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:23:11</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Final hostage remains return to Israel</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The remains of the last Israeli hostage in Gaza are returned home, paving the way for progress on the US plan for the enclave. We hear from a former Israeli hostage negotiator turned peace activist. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the dramatic end to the federal Liberal-National Coalition has the potential to reshape right-wing politics in Australia. While some are still working to get the Coalition back together, others say the break-up could lead to new opportunities for both parties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile we talk soaring temperatures, the energy grid and the Adelaide Writer's Festival with the South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And anti-vaping advocates say they have a program that could prevent problematic gambling behaviours in teenagers and young adults, and they're calling on the federal government to get behind it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220258</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220258</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h2/Z/4k.mp3" length="35261231" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:29</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Minnesota politicians condemn second ICE killing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There have been renewed protests and clashes with law enforcement in Minneapolis, after a man was shot dead by federal agents at the weekend. We hear from a Democratic State Senator as calls grow for ICE to leave the state. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of the federal Liberal and National parties have spent the weekend assessing the implications following another Coalition divorce. Deputy leader Ted O'Brien come on the program to back up his leader Sussan Ley. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Young Australian of the Year Nedd Brockman shares his vision to tackle homelessness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220306</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220306</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/h1/Z/4l.mp3" length="35137967" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:24</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: What is the future of NATO?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many are trying to gauge the future of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, so we're featuring two different perspectives. A former deputy NATO commander, and a former US envoy, who have different takes on the future of American involvement and what middle powers should be doing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we'll dive back into federal politics and the split between the Nationals and Liberal party. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220282</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/106220282</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/gu/Z/sv.mp3" length="34950191" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <itunes:duration>0:24:16</itunes:duration>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
