<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:ns1="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" xmlns:ns2="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:podcast="https://podcastindex.org/namespace/1.0" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
    <description>Filtered feed containing only Breakfast Wrap episodes from Radio National Breakfast</description>
    <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:07:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <ns0:link href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/breakfast-wrap.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="https://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" rel="hub"/>
    <ns1:guid>f95d7b89-e1ee-554c-be7f-f126f0b92dae</ns1:guid>
    <image>
      <url>https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg</url>
      <title>Radio National Breakfast - Breakfast Wrap</title>
      <link>https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/</link>
    </image>
    <ns2:image href="https://bigal.github.io/breakfast-wrap-feed/podcast-artwork.jpg"/>
    <ns2:author>ABC Radio National</ns2:author>
    <ns2:category text="News"/>
    <ns2:explicit>false</ns2:explicit>
    <ns2:owner/>
    <ns2:owner>
      <ns2:name>ABC Radio National</ns2:name>
      <ns2:email>podcasts@abc.net.au</ns2:email>
    </ns2:owner>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Optus blame game explained</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who knew what... and when... about the Optus triple zero outage? Those are the key questions asked this week in parliament following the disastrous outage linked to three deaths. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll get clarity on the timeline, and hear from the federal government. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the French President says he will name a new prime minister in the next 48 hours. Yet he's still under pressure to follow his ex-Prime Minister out the door too. One of his Renaissance party colleagues joins us. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Queensland, mining giant Glencore has accepted a $600 million support package from the state and federal governments to save its ailing sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll find out why an Australian has been hit with a 14 year prison sentence in absentia by Russia, over his role fighting in the war in Ukraine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105811264</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105811264</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dt/Z/05.mp3" length="23590272" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:00</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Two years on from October 7</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israelis gathered across the country overnight to mark the second anniversary of the October 7 Hamas attack, which saw about 1200 people killed and 251 hostages taken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Danny Majzner's sister,  Australian-Israeli Galit Carbone, was murdered at a Kibbutz on October 7.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, Mr Majzner will meet with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Minister for Foreign Affairs Penny Wong. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before the meeting, he spoke with Sally Sara. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today you will also hear from Jonathan Kuttab, a Palestinian human rights lawyer and co-founder of the Palestinian human rights group Al-Haq. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, in response to recent Optus triple-zero failures, the federal government has introduced a bill to create a "Triple Zero Custodian" , who would provide oversight on Australia's emergency system to detect any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But will this be enough to restore confidence in the system, particularly in regional and remote communities where finding adequate coverage and reception can be a day-to-day problem? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105807718</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105807718</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/ds/Z/vv.mp3" length="35386799" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:34</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Former Trump ally questions Gaza peace plan</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Former adviser to Mr Trump and US Ambassador to the UN, John Bolton tells us its "unlikely" the Gaza plan will happen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hear from the former Trump ally as indirect negotiations happen in Egypt, and Jewish communities around the world begin marking the second anniversary of October 7th.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, France loses its fifth prime minister in less than two years - we find out what the political climate is like in Paris. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And pressure is once again building on the federal government to address gambling harm,  more than two years after a landmark parliamentary report — also known as the "Murphy Report" — recommended sweeping reforms to tackle online gambling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105801888</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105801888</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/ds/Z/06.mp3" length="34890287" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:13</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: What does Hastie's exit mean for Ley's Liberals?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The resignation of West Australian Liberal MP Andrew Hastie from the opposition frontbench opens yet another wound for the Coalition as parliament resumes this week.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, polls have closed in Syria, where the country is holding its first parliamentary elections since the toppling of the regime of Bashar al-Assad. We'll learn why this vote is different to what you'd expect. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a new round of indirect ceasefire talks between Israel and Hamas begins in Egypt today, with the Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu saying he hopes to announce the release of hostages "in the coming days".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105800128</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105800128</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dq/Z/35.mp3" length="23801856" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:00</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Manchester reeling after deadly attack</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;British authorities have condemned a deadly terrorist attack on a Jewish synagogue in northern England.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two people have been killed and at least four others injured after an assailant drove a car into people outside the Manchester synagogue and then began stabbing them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll head to Manchester to hear from the community. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, at least five Australians are thought to be among those captured by the Israeli Defence Force from a flotilla which was bound for Gaza. We get a response to the situation from the federal government. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Deputy Prime Minister Richard Marles touts news that Papua New Guinea's cabinet has approved a landmark defence treaty with Australia, after the two countries failed to sign the agreement last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105792080</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105792080</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/do/Z/1p.mp3" length="35226671" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:27</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: What is the impact of the US government shutdown?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It's day one of a government shutdown in the United States, and hundreds of thousands of federal workers are bracing for missed paychecks,  while government operations grind to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Venezuelan President Nicolas Maduro says he's ready to declare a state of emergency amid reports the US military is drawing up options to target drug traffickers inside Venezuela. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, California has signed a new bill into law requiring top AI companies to fulfil transparency requirements and report AI-related safety incidents. So could and should Australia follow suit? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a Senate inquiry into aged care has called for an end to the "rationing" of home care packages, and the urgent release of more to ensure Australians aren't dying while waiting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105786488</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105786488</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dm/Z/ph.mp3" length="35867183" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:54</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: What the latest housing scheme means for house prices?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has it just got easier or harder to get into the property market?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The federal government's Home Guarantee Scheme is expanding today, meaning more Australians will only need to pay a five per cent deposit on a property.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the changes, there will be no income limits, meaning all first-time buyers are eligible. But it comes as new figures show eight months of consistent property price growth, so will this new scheme encourage that trend? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we're once again talking about a government shutdown in the United States - so why is this the system that Washington has to navigate? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll look at a proposed merger between two of the country's largest media companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105780016</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105780016</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dl/Z/5h.mp3" length="35545199" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:41</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Is Trump's Gaza proposal a plan for peace?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The White House has released a 20-point plan to end the ongoing war in Gaza, but is it a plan for peace?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You'll hear from the ABC's John Lyons, and two different Palestinian perspectives - Palestinian politician Mustafa Barghouthi and Gazan-American analyst Ahmed Fouad Alkhatib.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, a number of unregulated melatonin products sold in Australia have been found to be 400 per cent stronger than advertised,  while some had no active melatonin at all. So what's the warning to melatonin users?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And local artists, authors, and creatives are gathering at Parliament House today to speak out about the impact of artificial intelligence. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105774922</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105774922</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dj/Z/vl.mp3" length="35940911" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:57</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia's role in the space race</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australia is the centre of the known universe this week, as world leaders in space development and research meet in Sydney for the annual International Astronautical Congress.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new space race has begun, with billionaires Elon Musk and Jeff Bezos leading the way and the Australian government encouraging local industry to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, confusion remains about exactly how many Australian companies will be impacted by looming US pharmaceutical tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week the US President announced that from October, the US will impose a 100 per cent tariff on branded or patented pharmaceutical imports, unless a pharmaceutical company builds a manufacturing plant in the US - so what could it mean for Australian industry?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Prime Minister has wrapped up a visit to the UK with an address to the Labour party conference in Liverpool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the speech, Mr Albanese vowed to defend democracy itself while standing alongside the man he described as his "mate": British PM Sir Keir Starmer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes after the Australian PM leaned into the comfort of the Commonwealth, enjoying lunch with King Charles at Balmoral Castle in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105772674</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105772674</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dj/Z/19.mp3" length="36124079" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:25:05</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: How has Australia fared on the world stage?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Australia took to the world stage at the UN General Assembly, officially recognising the State of Palestine and touting its incoming social media laws, the PM also booked a long-awaited one-on-one meeting with the US President Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll wrap the week with our Friday political panel, the acting Prime Minister Richard Marles, and the Shadow Trade Minister Kevin Hogan. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, something different - the race to mine the moon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You'll hear from a company making very real plans to start a resources industry on the lunar surface. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105764996</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105764996</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dg/Z/u8.mp3" length="35682291" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:46</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Greta Thunberg details attack on aid flotilla</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We hear from activist Greta Thunberg who says her Gaza-bound flotilla has come under attack, south of Greece. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She told us vessels were targeted by drones overnight, there were a number of explosions, and while there were no injuries, some boats sustained damage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spain and Greece have both announced Naval support for the flotilla. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, as more deadlocks delay efforts to secure peace in Gaza and the release of hostages, we hear from a father whose son has been held for nearly two years. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has finally locked in a formal face-to-face meeting with the US President for next month, so how can we assess relations with Washington?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And for something completely different, we speak to the world's fastest woman. An Australian who's retained her title at the world cup of speed skidiving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105756730</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105756730</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/df/Z/s8.mp3" length="36101039" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:25:04</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: A mother's mission for teen social media restrictions</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bathurst lawyer Emma Mason will today tell the story of her late teenage daughter to the UN General Assembly in the hope that other nations will follow Australia's lead on restricting access to social media for teenagers. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her 15 year-old daughter Tilly died by suicide after a prolonged period of bullying on social media, which included the use of fake nude imagery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emma Mason speaks to us ahead of her UN address.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A warning that today's program discusses suicide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the US Ambassador to Israel Mike Huckabee tells us that Australia has made a very serious mistake in recognising the state of Palestine and has described US-Australia relations as reaching a "point of stress".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We'll also get reaction to yesterday's interview with a Gaza doctor with Australia's former foreign minister Bob Carr. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then as international calls for a ceasefire in Gaza mount, concerns have been raised about the role of Australian citizens fighting in the Israel Defense Forces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105751986</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105751986</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/de/Z/rv.mp3" length="23966208" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:57</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: 'No point recognising Palestine when its all gone'</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australian doctor Saya Aziz shares her experience working in Gaza City's Al Shifa hospital the day after Australia's recognition of Palestine. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also hear from Australia's Foreign Minister Penny Wong who is in New York for the UN General Assembly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we ask Coalition Senator and former Australian Ambassador to Israel Dave Sharma why Sussan Ley has written to Republicans to say the Coalition would undo the government's move.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105747290</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105747290</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dd/Z/sv.mp3" length="36003119" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:25:00</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia recognises Palestine</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australia has officially recognised Palestine as a sovereign state, in a move it hopes will build momentum for a two-state solution. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap hears from Francesca Albanese, the UN Special Rapporteur for Palestinian Human Rights. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then we'll head to Arizona where US President Donald Trump and prominent members of his “Make America Great Again” movement have paid tribute to the late conservative activist Charlie Kirk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the South Australian Prime Minister weighs in on the Optus outage, that meant more than 600 calls to emergency services failed, resulting in multiple deaths. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105746316</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105746316</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/dc/Z/rh.mp3" length="35991599" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:59</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Is Australia's new emissions reduction target enough?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The federal government has committed to a target to cut emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035, based on 2005 levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labor says the target is both ambitious and achievable, but there's criticism from the opposition and the cross-bench that the range is either too high or too low.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we'll hear from both sides of politics, as well as what the science says, and the response from Australia's neighbours in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, with Jimmy Kimmel out of the way, US President Donald Trump is threatening more American broadcasters - we'll get the latest from Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105736160</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105736160</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/da/Z/nb.mp3" length="35364335" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:33</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: PM fails to secure second Pacific deal</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Prime Minister has returned home from Papua New Guinea without a defence deal - going zero from two in the Pacific. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PNG Prime Minister James Marape has now announced his defence minister will instead head overseas for talks with other nations about the Australia pact, with China the first stop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It marks the second Pacific setback for Australia this month, with a $500 million security and economic deal with Vanuatu remaining unsigned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap hears from the Opposition and the Greens. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, the stadium saga in Tasmania, as the state's planning committee says no to the big build. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And we'll end with the pomp and ceremony at Windsor castle, where Donald Trump is being treated to a historic second state visit. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105732834</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105732834</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d9/Z/jf.mp3" length="35847599" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:53</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Israel committing genocide in Gaza, says UN report</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to a UN Commission of Inquiry established by the UN Human Rights Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inquiry has found Israeli authorities "intended to kill as many Palestinians as possible" and have committed the crime against humanity of extermination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israel's Ministry of Foreign Affairs categorically rejected the report, denouncing it as "distorted and false". &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today we interrogate an Israeli defence of its war in Gaza, and hear from an international legal expert who has previously probed Israel's conduct in war. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then - an extraordinary moment between an Australian journalist and US President Donald Trump. ABC America's Editor John Lyons shares what its like to be ripped into by the President. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105725068</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105725068</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d8/Z/hp.mp3" length="35737007" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:49</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Does Sussan Ley's leadership hinge on net zero?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coverage and analysis of national and international events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105723248</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105723248</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d7/Z/jq.mp3" length="35141999" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:24</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Australia pours $12 billion into WA AUKUS precinct</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Australia commits 12 billion dollars to developing an AUKUS shipbuilding facility in Western Australia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So how closely is the US watching this spending spree? And has the announcement been timed to coincide with Anthony Albanese's trip to New York, where he'll try to land a face-to-face meeting with President Donald Trump&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap hears from Federal Minister for Science, Industry and Innovation Tim Ayres, and Shadow Defence Minister Angus Taylor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We also have the latest from the right-wing protests in the UK, and the summit of Arab and Islamic nations in Qatar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105718820</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105718820</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 09:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d6/Z/i7.mp3" length="25767168" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:26:50</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: How America's latest assassination is already dividing the country</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As authorities hunt for the gunman responsible for Charlie Kirk's assassination, his death is already beginning to divide parts of American society. Before a suspect has been identified and a motive found, the President is already lashing out at "radical left lunatics".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast Wrap hears from journalists in the US who have interviewed Charlie Kirk. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, for decades, the remains of more than 170 people have been on display at the University of Tasmania's RA Rodda Pathology Museum without the knowledge or consent of their loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last night, the Tasmanian Coroner's Office published findings from an investigation into how and why these remains were taken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105708964</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105708964</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d4/Z/c8.mp3" length="35605103" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:43</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: The assassination of Charlie Kirk</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Charlie Kirk  - one of America's most high-profile conservative activists has been shot dead at an event at a Utah university.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the latest in a recent string of violence against political figures in the United States. We'll take a look at who he was and the mark he leaves on American politics. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has likened Israel's targeting of Hamas leaders in Qatar to America's pursuit of al-Qaida after the 9/11 attacks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qatar has condemned the Israeli strikes targeting Hamas officials in Doha as a "criminal assault" and a "blatant violation of all international laws and norms".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plus, Poland has shot down Russian drones after it says Moscow repeatedly violated its air-space. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105702322</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105702322</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d3/Z/bd.mp3" length="35708783" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:47</ns2:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Wrap: Israel strikes Qatar</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who knew what and when about Israel's strikes in Doha, that are being condemned around the world as a flagrant breach of Qatar's sovereignty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At least six people have been killed in the attack targeting senior Hamas figures in Doha. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Qatar has slammed the attack as a "criminal assault" and a "blatant violation of all international laws and norms", saying it threatened the security of its people. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then, we'll turn to the Prime Minister's trip to the Pacific and the challenges being raised by domestic politics in the region. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the Victorian Government has tabled a historic Treaty Bill in parliament with the aim of holding the government to account over policies impacting the First Peoples of Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victoria is the first state to make such a move, and if the legislation is passed, it will make the First Peoples' Assembly permanent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recap the morning's news, politics and global affairs with the Breakfast Wrap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105698490</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.abc.net.au/listen/programs/radionational-breakfast/radio-national-breakfast/105698490</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://mediacore-live-production.akamaized.net/audio/02/d2/Z/9r.mp3" length="35873519" type="audio/mpeg"/>
      <ns2:duration>0:24:54</ns2:duration>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
